<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jquinny.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://jquinny.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-01-03T22:51:10+00:00</updated><id>https://jquinny.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><entry><title type="html">Blog Overview</title><link href="https://jquinny.github.io/blog/2024/blog-overview/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog Overview"/><published>2024-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jquinny.github.io/blog/2024/blog-overview</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jquinny.github.io/blog/2024/blog-overview/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello and welcome to my blog. Not really sure how this will turn out, but my hope is that there will be a tidbit of knowledge that someone finds just as cool as I do in here. My rational for starting this was twofold:</p> <ol> <li>Trying to jam all the information you’ve learned about a topic into a concise and readable form seems like a good way to pressure test true understanding</li> <li>I’ve been saved various times by random blogs containing just the right piece of information I needed to overcome some silly bug or big hurdle in a project, so I hope to be able to help another lost soul some day</li> </ol> <p>It also just seems like a good way to practice developing my own voice and way of explaining the nonsense in my head, so there is that too :)</p> <p>There are just way too many things I find interesting and want to learn, spanning topics in computer science (my domain of expertise), cognitive science, philosophy, and beyond. I want to understand the deep inner workings of not only some esoteric topics in computer science, but the fundamental driving forces of the human mind and nature. I have a real bad habit of bouncing around gathering a cursory bit of knowledge on many subjects, but in my experience true joy has come from learning things on a deeper level. Thus, we arrive at the “what” that these blogs will be about.</p> <p>I’ve decided to try out a Topic of The Month style of extracurricular learning as a means of avoiding a scattered learning experience. I do not know how well this will work in practice, but my idea is to spend a month learning about some specific topic like deep learning object detection models in computer vision, or maybe something philosophical like Aristotelian ethics (idk why that was the first thing to come to mind after object detection but oh well). I will spend the month focusing my extra learning time (outside of school or work) on this one subject, and accumulate what I learn into a blog post at the end of the month. With that said, see you in February (hopefully).</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[brief overview of what my blogs will be about and why I decided to do them]]></summary></entry></feed>